So yesterday we used Cursor to build out
our project. Today we are going to use
GitHub Copilot or at least I am. You can
use whichever one you want. Of course
you're probably a dab hand with Cursor
now. So you can stick with that if you
like it. Uh depending on on how far
through your your quote you are. But
here I am in GitHub and I've gone to my
my GitHub page. This is just my my
profile page. I'm going to go up here to
my avatar menu and select co-pilot
settings to look into this. Now I am on
the co-pilot pro plan and you might be
on just the free plan that you remember
just has a certain quot of requests that
you can make. This has a larger quotota
and I could I could have a uh I could
pay more and have an even bigger quotota
but as I am right now I have used 1.4%
4% of my premium requests and it resets
monthly and uh yeah so so that's going
to be uh what what I can consume and it
tells me here that it's enabled to be
used in in github.com in a CLI or in the
IDE which is where we have been using it
and where we will again today and
there's also here options to select to
turn on and off different models and so
on. So it's worth worth looking at the
different different uh settings that
you've got here. Um, and uh, most
importantly, keep an eye on usage. This
is where you can see what you're using
according to your plan. So, that's one
thing I wanted to show you. I also
wanted to show you something that will
be linked in the resources, which is the
repo that we'll be using. It's a repo
called PM. It's private for me right
now, but it'll be public by the time you
see it, I hope. And it's the usual
story. I'm going to ask you to come to
this green code button and just uh on
usually select https and copy that to
the clipboard. You don't need to do this
because it will also be in the
resources. But this this uh address here
which is the address of this repo that's
what we will clone to get started with
this project. And so here I am in VS
Code. Remember this similar to cursor.
This is the welcome screen. And I'm
going to bring up a terminal by pressing
controll back tick and up it comes.
There is a terminal also of course on
the view menu. You know this now. And
I'm going to go into my projects
directory, cd projects. Look at where I
am. pwd is where I am. I'm in user z
projects. Yours might look different,
but that kind of idea. And I'm now going
to type git clone and then the link to
that uh that repo that's called pm.git.
Or you can just take this entire command
from the course resources. That's what
you do next. I'm not going to run that
because I've already done it. I've
already got a PM directory. Look, if I
do cdpm, I'm in it right now. And that
is where you will hopefully uh be able
to go into as well. Now, let's open that
project. And so to open the new project,
you can go to the file menu, new window,
or you can just press open right here.
And then just uh find your way to your
projects folder, and then find your way
to PM, which should have been cloned. Go
into it. Press open. That's the way to
do it. You know you're in the right
place cuz PM appears here. Do you trust
the order? Yes, I trust the authors.
Yes. If it says uh it's if you get that
then then yes, you trust me, right? Uh
and now we are in PM. Here we are. We've
got ourselves uh everything set up. Now,
you may have on your mind that that you
don't like the fact that I brought you
into an existing repo. You might be
thinking, I'd rather build everything
from scratch. But I have a reason for
this. Uh sometimes we'll build
everything from scratch, but sometimes
we won't. And here's why. The thing is
that building things from scratch is
actually much easier with vibe coding,
with aentic coding, because agents are
great at building things from absolute
nothing. They're able to build all the
scaffolding themselves. They're able to
set up all the right files. They're able
to take it through step by step. It's
actually harder when you're starting
with something. And one of the the
hardest is when you're starting with a
large legacy project, which we will
cover at some point in our journey. But
but for now, what I want to do is a
little mix up in that there's going to
be some code that we're inheriting as
part of building this project and then
something new that we're going to be
building. Most of it will be new, but
there'll be something here already. And
what is that thing already, you're
wondering? Well, you're going to love
this. What we've got already is the
Cananban front end that Codeex made
earlier this week. The really cool
canban view. I'm going to I'm going to
pretend that that wasn't vibe coded.
Just that we've got that here. that
that's been built by somebody else, by
another team. That MVP is already being
built as a front end. We know it was
vibe coded, but but but we're just going
to pretend we've inherited it. We've got
that. And our mission is to turn this
into an application with a proper front
end, backend, database, API, with
everything together. So, this could
actually be a project management tool
that would be persistent. That's what
we're going to build. We're going to
going to turn this into the real deal.
and we're gonna do it with LLMs. And
actually, when I say we're going to do
it with LLMs, I mean that in two ways.
We're going to use, of course, a coding
agent to write this, but also we're
going to build a project management app
that has an AI feature because doesn't
everything have an AI feature these
days? It's going to have a chat with my
project ability that you'll be able to
to ask questions about the project
setup. You'll also be able to to ask for
things to be done to the project through
an AI chat interface. We're going to
build an AI application as well. Well, I
hope you're excited. I certainly am.
Okay, so let me just take you through
the file system here on the left. But I
do also want to remind you a few things
about actually using GitHub Copilot here
on the right. If you've forgotten, we've
got this agent drop down here that lets
us choose the mode we're working on.
We've got the model selector where we
can choose which models we want to have
with a manage models button that will
bring up this this whole section with
all of the details of the the models.
This is also where you could choose if
you want to be be working with free
models to be using OAMA locally and
running a model on your local machine if
you've got strong enough local machine
and you can run it for free. And
remember to look in the course resources
for more on that. But if you're looking
at at using Copilot properly, then then
also down here, remember this thing here
gives us a sense of of how much room
we've got. And you can see that the
premium requests I've I've not uh not
used up many of them and they reset
quite soon for me. And you can press
this manage paid premium requests and it
will open you up in GitHub. And this is
where you can set your kind of budget
limits and things like that should you
wish to go over the allotted the free
portion that you get automatically.
Okay. So that's just oriented you over
it there on the right. Now I want to
orient you on the files on the left.
What is set up for you right away. Now
what I've got here is first of all a
directory structure. Front end is where
we've got the existing camban MVP. back
end is empty except for an agents.mmd
that is empty. It says this will
something will go here. Front uh scripts
is also empty except for something that
that says things will go here. I've got
thev file which is the same one as
before. I just copied it across. You
should be able to do that too. Or if you
want you can create a new one. Remember
open routter API key in block capitals.
Paste in the key if you're going to
create it from scratch. No mistakes
allowed. Uh, but you could also just
copy it from where it is somewhere else.
Be careful with that MV file. TheGit
ignore file is actually one of the
defaults. It's got all the sorts of
stuff you typically want to ignore,
including the EMV file that you never
want to check into Git. And then last,
but very much not least, I have prepared
an agents.md
file to walk you through right now. That
is that is positioning us for success.
That is where we begin. And you
shouldn't feel like you have to use what
I've got right here. I'm doing right
click and open preview to bring it up
looking fancy. Don't feel like you have
to do this. You can take this in
whatever direction you want. I just
wrote this right now. So, so, uh, this
isn't isn't like I I sort of spent ages
preparing it, but rather than you
sitting there, well, I type it, I just
did it quickly. And this is what I've
gone. I've tried to be reasonably
scrappy because we want the the agent to
to go with us on this. So, we're
building a project management MVP web
app. It is uh a user should be able to
sign in. When they're signed in, they
will see a cananban board representing
their project. It has fixed columns that
can be renamed. The cards can be moved.
There is an AI chat feature in the
sidebar. The AI is able to create, edit,
or move one or more cards. Limitations
for the MVP. There'll only be a single
user sign in hardcoded user and
password, but the database should
support having many users for the
future. There will only be one can board
per signed in user. We're not going to
have lots of different boards and it's
going to run locally in a Docker
container for the MVP. We're not going
to deploy it out somewhere. That's not
to say that you can't easily do that.
Technical decisions. So this part I have
written based on my my opinion, my
technical opinion. And you would be in
absolutely fair to say okay but how are
we to know what to put here? And the
answer is you don't need to know what to
put there because you could just ask an
AI. You could just ask the the the agent
I was going to say the cursor agent, the
GitHub co-pilot over here to do it for
you. Now I have a viewpoint. I want an
Nex.js front end because I want to show
that to you and because that's what
we've already got. I want the Python
backend to be fast API. Python is what I
do. So I know that stuff well. So I have
opinions on this. Uh I want everything
packaged into a Docker container. that
makes most sense for us right now. I
want to use UV as the package manager.
And honestly, these these agents don't
like to do that. They like to use
simpler things, the usual pip. I like UV
because I love UV and so I I want to use
it. You don't need to if you don't want
to. Um I want to use open router for the
AI calls because that makes most sense
for us. I'm telling it the open router
API key is in the MV file in the project
routt. I'm telling it the model I'd like
to use. You can use the free variant.
you remember it's just got the word free
after it colon free I think colon free
if you want to use the free variant um
with which you'll find in the open
router website or you can use whatever
model you want and I'm saying I want to
use a SQL light local database for the
database of course there are many other
ways of doing it if you for example have
a superbase account where you've got
already data the ability to have
databases running on the cloud you could
instead just put your superbase keys in
the MV it will all work great that works
too but we're going to keep it Super
simple for this. And then current state
a working MVP of the front end has been
built and is already in front end. This
is not yet designed for the Docker
setup. It's a pure front end only demo.
Current state's a bit awkward there,
isn't it? Why don't we why don't we call
that starting point? That seems more
clear. Otherwise, it's it's only going
to get confusing when it sees that
that's not the current state later on.
So, let's say starting point. Um, okay.
And then I've got the same color scheme
as before. the coding standards. I think
this is basically the same as before. I
might I maybe added uh added the the
fourth one here. When hitting issues,
always identify root cause. Do not
guess. Prove with evidence, then fix the
root cause. All just standard stuff I
like to use, but increasingly it's not
needed. And then finally, working
documentation. All documents for
planning. Oh, typo. All documents for
planning and executing this project will
be in the docs directory. Please review
docs plan. MD document before
proceeding. What is this document, you
ask? Let's go look at that next.